Register to The David Kraehenbuehl Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Music, Series I
  - Music by David Kraehenbuehl
    - Choral Music, I.E
      - [Drumfire; arr.] Drumfire: a cantata against war / by David Kraehenbuehl; text by Goff Owen, Sr. -- c.1986 by Goff Owen, Jr., 1 manuscript score (85 p.); 28 cm. (Box 5, Folder 66)
        Short score in C, with accompaniment reduced to 2-4 staves, instrumental cues.
      - Le grant desir.
        see: [Chansons. Le grant desir]
      - The heavens, they are many / by David Kraehenbuehl. -- c.1964 by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript score (6 p.); 35 cm. (Box 5, Folder 67)
        Holograph in ink, small cut-outs in score.
        For SATB chorus and organ.
        On title page: Written for The Reorganized Church of Jesus Christ of Latter Day Saints, Washington, D.C., 1964.
        At end: Princeton, N.J., April 3, 1964.
      - [Heavens, they are many. Choral score] The heavens, they are many / by David Kraehenbuehl. -- c.1964 by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript choral score (8 p.); 28 cm. (Box 5, Folder 67)
      - [Heavens, they are many. Choral score] The heavens, they are many / by David Kraehenbuehl. -- c.1964 by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript choral score (8 p.); 23 cm. (Box 5, Folder 67)
      - Ideo gloria in excelsis deo.
        see: [Christmas choruses, no. 2. Ideo gloria in excelsis deo]
      - In praise of marriage.
        see also A wedding anthem.
      - In praise of marriage: a triptych of Psalms for SA, TB, or SATB and piano 4-hands / David Kraehenbuehl -- c.1957 by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript score (14 p.); 35 cm. (Box 5, Folder 68)
        Psalm 127. -- Psalm 128. -- Psalm 134.
        At end: Princeton, N.J., September 8, 1957.
        In envelope (discarded) marked: Transcription for voice, piano 4 hands.
      - In praise of marriage: a triptych of Psalms for SA, TB, or SATB and piano 4-hands / David Kraehenbuehl -- c.1957 by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript score (14 p.); 35 cm. (Box 5, Folder 68)
        Photocopy of holograph, annotations in pencil and colored ink.
      - [In praise of marriage. Choral score] In praise of marriage: a triptych of Psalms for SA, TB, or SATB and accompaniment / David Kraehenbuehl -- c.1957 by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript choral score (7 p.); 28 cm. (Box 5, Folder 69)
        At end: Sept. 8, 1957.
      - [In praise of marriage; arr.] In praise of marriage: setting for 2- or 4- voice chorus and organ / by David Kraehenbuehl. -- c.1995 by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 score (21 p.); 28 cm. (Box 5, Folder 69)
        On title page: 1957.
      - Make us true servants / [text by] Susan G. Wente; [music by] David Kraehenbuehl. -- c.1982 by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript score (4 p.); 30 cm. (Box 5, Folder 70)
        For 2-part chorus and keyboard.
        At end: 2'20", In honor of St. Francis, October 4, 1982, La Crosse, Wisconsin.
        In envelope (discarded) marked: St. Joseph the Worker Cathedral Choir, 1982-3.
      - Make us true servants / setting by David Kraehenbuehl; [text by] Susan G. Wente. -- c.1982 by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 score (6 p.); 28 cm. (Box 5, Folder 70)
        For 2-part chorus (women, men) and organ.
      - A nuptial triptych: for SA, TB, or SATB and wind orchestra / David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript score (10 p.) + 15 manuscript parts (27 p. total); 44 and 28 cm. (Box 17, Folder 234)
        I. Psalm 127. -- II. Psalm 128. -- III. Psalm 134.
        "Set for the New Haven Chorale in recollection of a brilliant performance of the Mozart Litany and Vespers."
        At end: Sept. 8, 1957, New Haven, Conn.
      - Our Father have mercy on us who gather wood / text: Ellen Kort; music: David Kraehenbuehl. -- music c.1988 by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript score (22 p.) + 1 manuscript part (3 p.); 28 cm. (Box 5, Folder 71)
        Holograph score in ink, annotations in colored pencil.
        For SATB chorus, oboe, and piano.
        On title page: Written for the White Heron Chorale on the occasion of its 10th anniversary.
        At end: 8' 40", September 18, 1988, Trempealeau, Wisconsin.
      - [Our Father have mercy on us who gather wood. Choral score] Our Father have mercy on us who gather wood / text: Ellen Kort; music: David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript choral score (9 p.); 28 cm. (Box 5, Folder 71)
        Holograph score in ink.
      - Petitions: a motet cycle of the greater antiphons for SATB a cappella / David Kraehenbuehl. -- c.1957 by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript score (15 p.); 28 cm. (Box 5, Folder 72)
        Text in Latin, based on the Advent "O" antiphons.
        On title page: Written for the Cappella Cordina.
        At end: New Haven, Conn., 12/12/57.
      - Petitions: a motet cycle of the greater antiphons for SATB a cappella / David Kraehenbuehl. -- c.1957 by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript score (15 p.); 22 cm. (Box 5, Folder 72)
      - Petitions: a motet-cycle based on the great antiphons for Advent / David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript score (18 p.); 24 cm. (Box 5, Folder 72)
        At end: To Cappella Cordina, December 12, 1957, New Haven, Conn.
      - Petitions: a setting of the Advent "O" antiphons: SATB chorus unaccompanied / by David Kraehenbuehl. c.1995 by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 score (18 p.); 28 cm. (Box 5, Folder 72)
        Text in Latin.
      - Prayers from the ark: SAB and organ / text: Carmen Bernos de Gasztold; music: David Kraehenbuehl. -- text c.1962 by Rumer Godden, music c.1968 by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript score (18 p.); 35 cm. (Box 5, Folder 73)
        1. Noah's prayer. -- 2. Prayer of the bee. -- 3. Prayer of the monkey. -- 4. Prayer of the butterfly. -- 5. Prayer of the elephant. -- 6. Prayer of the dove.
        On title page: Written for St. John's Lutheran Church, Summit, New Jersey.
        At end: Cranbury, N.J., June 30, 1968.
      - [Prayers from the ark. Choral score] Prayers from the ark: SAB and organ / text: Carmen Bernos de Gasztold; music: David Kraehenbuehl. -- 1968., 1 manuscript score (11 p.); 28 cm. (Box 5, Folder 73)
        On title page: Written for St. John's Lutheran Church, Summit, N.J.
      - [Prayers from the ark. Choral score] Prayers from the ark: SAB and organ / text: Carmen Bernos de Gasztold; music: David Kraehenbuehl. -- 1968., 1 manuscript score (11 p.); 22 cm. (Box 5, Folder 73)
      - Psalm 121: set for 2-voice choir with organ / by David Kraehenbuehl. -- c.1985 by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript score (11 p.); 31 cm. (Box 5, Folder 74)
        At end: 4' 00", Trempealeau, WI, June 27, 1985.
        In envelope marked: For St. James Church, Rocky Hill, N.J.
      - Psalm 121 / David Kraehenbuehl. -- c.1985 by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript score (11 p.); 28 cm. (Box 5, Folder 74)
      - Psalm 121 / setting by David Kraehenbuehl. -- c.1985 by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 score (11 p.); 28 cm. (Box 5, Folder 74)
        At end: 4' 00"
      - A song against bores.
        see: [Christmas choruses, no. 4. A song against bores]
      - The star song.
        see: [Christmas choruses, no. 1. The star song]
      - Take up your cross: two-voice chorus and organ / David Kraehenbuehl. -- c.1982 by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript score (3 p.); 30 cm. (Box 5, Folder 75)
        Holograph in ink, annotations in pencil and liquid paper.
        At end: August 22, 1982, La Crosse, Wisconsin.
        In envelope (discarded) marked: St. Joseph the Worker Cathedral Choir, 1982-83.
      - Take up your cross / setting by David Kraehenbuehl; [text by] William W. Everest. -- c.1982 by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 score (7 p.); 28 cm. (Box 5, Folder 75)
      - Te Deum: for SATB and organ (optional brass) / by David Kraehenbuehl. -- music c.1975 by David Kraehenbuehl; text c.1975 by ICET., 1 manuscript score (11 p.) + 4 manuscript parts (4 p. total); 35 and 28 cm. (Box 5, Folder 76)
        Optional brass parts for trumpet I, trumpet II, trombone I, and trombone II.
        On title page: For the Trenton Diocesan Choir.
        At end: Laus Deo! September 9, 1975, Cranbury, N.J.
      - Te Deum: for SATB and organ (optional brass) / by David Kraehenbuehl. -- music c.1975 by David Kraehenbuehl; text c.1975 by ICET., 1 manuscript score (11 p.); 28 cm. (Box 5, Folder 76)
        Optional brass: trumpet I, trumpet II, trombone I, and trombone II.
      - [Te Deum. Choral score] Te Deum / by David Kraehenbuehl. -- music c.1975 by David Kraehenbuehl; text c.1975 by ICET., 1 manuscript choral score (10 p.); 28 cm. (Box 5, Folder 76)
        At end: September 9, 1975, Cranbury, N.J.
    - Early Works, I.G
      - There is no rose.
        see: [Christmas choruses, no. 3. There is no rose]
      - A wedding anthem: Psalm 127 / David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript score (5 p.); 29 cm. (Box 5, Folder 77)
        For 2-part chorus and keyboard (organ or piano)
        At end: August 19, 1956. To Donald and Anne Loach in honor of a most happy occasion, DK.
        Transposed and used as the first movement of In praise of marriage.
      - Weep willow.
        see: [Chansons. Weep willow]
      - Welcome, Yule: a Christmas madrigal for four-part chorus of women's voices a cappella / [text] Anon.; [music by] David Kraehenbuehl. -- New York: Associated Music Publishers, c.1955., 1 score (10 p.); 26 cm. (Box 5, Folder 78)
        "This piece, which may also be performed by men's voice (TTBB), was written for the Yale Freshman Chorus."
        Pl. no.: AMP-95524
      - When you're out of sight, I'm out of my mind.
        see: [Chansons. Car vrayment]
    - Vocal Music, I.F
      - The camel's complaint / words by Francis Carryl; [music by] David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript score (7 p.) + 1 manuscript part (2 p.); 28 cm. (Box 5, Folder 79)
        Holograph in pencil, p.7 of score and viola part are photocopies of manuscript.
        For soprano, viola, and piano.
        At end: For the Harsanyi family, Princeton, N.J., April 13, 1961.
      - Cantica sancti evangelii secundum Lucam / by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript score (15 p.) + 8 manuscript parts (21 p.); 44 and 35 cm. (Box 17, Folder 235)
        For soprano, tenor, flute, bassoon, trombone, viola, violoncello.
        Text from the Gospel of St. Luke.
        I. Canticum Zachariae. -- II. Canticum Beatae Mariae Virginis. -- III. Canticum Simeonis.
        On title page: Commissioned by the Harvard Musical Association, Boston, 1958.
        At end: New Haven, Conn., Sept. 7, 1958.
      - Confirmation Song.
        see: Who am I?
      - The crucifixion
        see: Sermons for the blessed.
      - Gott ist mein Mittelpunkt.
        see: [Sacred songs, voice, instruments (2)]
      - Der guldene Begriff.
      - Landscapes / David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript score (50 p.) + 6 manuscript parts (29 p. total); 35 cm. (Box 5, Folder 80)
        For soprano, flute, oboe, violin 1, violin 2, viola, violoncello.
        1. New Hampshire. -- 2. Virginia. -- 3. Usk. -- 4. Rannoch by Glencoe. -- 5. Cape Ann.
        At end: Dedicated to Josephine Vadala, Manitou Springs, Colorado, 4 May 1952.
      - [Sacred songs, voice, instruments (2)], 1 manuscript score (6 p.); 35 cm. (Box 5, Folder 81)
        For voice and 2 unspecified instruments, or for 3 instruments.
        Gott ist mein Mittelpunkt. -- Wer in sich über sich in Gott verreisen kann. -- Der guldene Begriff.
        Cues at beginning for clarinet, viola, bassoon.
      - Sea-diptych / [music by] David Kraehenbuehl; text -- Carl Sandburg., 1 manuscript score (3 p.); 32 cm. (Box 5, Folder 82)
        For tenor and piano.
        I. Sea-wash. -- II. Throw roses.
        Inscribed: For Goff Owen, tenor, David Kraehenbuehl, June 26, 1956.
      - Sea-diptych / [music by] David Kraehenbuehl; [text by] Carl Sandburg., 1 manuscript score (4 p.); 28 cm. (Box 5, Folder 82)
        At end: June 26, 1956, for Goff Owen.
      - Sea-diptych / [music by] David Kraehenbuehl; [text by] Carl Sandburg., 1 manuscript score (4 p.); 28 cm. (Box 5, Folder 82)
      - Sermons for the blessed: for baritone, mezzo-soprano, and orchestra / poems by James Weldon Johnson; music by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript score (50 p.) + 14 manuscript parts (48 p. total); 44 and 35 cm. (Box 17, Folder 236)
        I. The Crucifixion. -- II. Sister Caroline.
        At end of The Crucifixion: For Richard Owens, July 4, 1955, June 2, 1958, New Haven, Conn.
        At end of Sister Caroline: For Blanche Porto, December 27, 1957, June 22, 1958, New Haven, Conn.
      - [Sermons for the blessed. Crucifixion. Vocal score] The crucifixion: a sermon for baritone and piano / [text by] James Weldon Johnson; [music by] David Kraehenbuehl. -- text c.1927 by The Viking Press, 1955 by Grace Nail Johnson., 1 manuscript score (13 p.); 35 cm. (Box 5, Folder 83)
        At end: For Richard Owens, July 4, 1955, New Haven, Conn.
      - [Sermons for the blessed. Crucifixion. Vocal score] The crucifixion: a sermon for baritone and piano / [text by] James Weldon Johnson; [music by] David Kraehenbuehl. -- text c.1927 by The Viking Press, 1955 by Grace Nail Johnson., 1 manuscript vocal score (13 p.); 36 cm. (Box 5, Folder 83)
      - [Sermons for the blessed. Crucifixion. Vocal score] The crucifixion: sermon for baritone / by David Kraehenbuehl; [text by] James Weldon Johnson. -- text c.1927 by The Viking Press, 1955 by Grace Nail Johnson., 1 manuscript score (13 p.); 28 cm. (Box 5, Folder 83)
      - [Sermons for the blessed. Sister Caroline. Vocal score] A funeral sermon: for mezzo-soprano and piano / words by James Weldon Johnson; [music by] David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript vocal score (16 p.); 28 cm. (Box 5, Folder 83)
        Optional baritone part, pp. 14-16.
        At end: New Haven, Conn., Dec. 28, 1957.
        In envelope (discarded) marked: Original soprano aria -- Sister Caroline
      - [Sermons for the blessed. Sister Caroline. Vocal score] A funeral sermon: for mezzo-soprano and piano / words by James Weldon Johnson; [music by] David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript vocal score (16 p.); 28 cm. (Box 5, Folder 83)
        In envelope (discarded) marked as above.
      - Sister Caroline
        see: Sermons for the blessed
      - Songs of Ariel: for soprano, flute, and keyboard; texts by William Shakespeare; music by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript score (9 p.); 35 cm. (Box 5, Folder 84)
        I. Invitation. -- II. Reveille. -- III. Elegy. -- IV. Libertad.
        "Written for Frank McMullen and the Yale Drama School production of The Tempest, March 18-21, 1959."
        At end: New Haven, Conn., February 15, 1959.
      - Songs of Ariel / David Kraehenbuehl. -- c.1995 by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 score (12 p.) + 1 part (7 p.); 28 cm. (Box 5, Folder 84)
        For voice, flute, and keyboard.
        Text by William Shakespeare.
      - [Songs of Ariel. Vocal score] Songs of Ariel / [text by] William Shakespeare; [music by] David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript score (9 p.); 35 cm. (Box 5, Folder 84)
        For voice and piano.
        At end: February 15, 1959, New Haven, Conn.
      - [Songs of Ariel. Vocal score] Songs of Ariel / [text by] William Shakespeare; [music by] David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript score (9 p.); 28 cm. (Box 5, Folder 84)
      - [Songs of Ariel. Vocal score] Songs of Ariel / David Kraehenbuehl. -- c.1995 by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 score (12 p.); 28 cm. (Box 5, Folder 84)
      - [Songs of Ariel. Sketches], 4 manuscript scores (total 13 p.); 32 cm. (Box 5, Folder 84)
        For Ariel [voice], flute, and harpsichord.
        Come Unto These Yellow Sands, pg. 21 -- While you here do SNORING Lie, p. 39 -- Full Fadom Five, pg. 21B -- Where the bee sucks, pg. 81.
      - A very special house: a reading to music / text by Ruth Krauss; music by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript score (11 p.) + 5 manuscript parts; 44 and 35 cm. (Box 17, Folder 237)
        For reader, oboe, B clarinet, bassoon, B trumpet, trombone.
        At end: October 11, 1958, New Haven, Conn.
      - A very special house: a reading to music / text by Ruth Krauss; music by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript score (11 p.) + 5 manuscript parts; 46 and 36 cm. (Box 17, Folder 237)
      - [Very special house; arr.] A very special house., 1 manuscript score (11 p.); 31 cm. (Box 5, Folder 85)
        Arr. for narrator and piano.
      - Wer in sich über sich in Gott verreisen kann.
      - Who am I? / [text by] Sr. James Margaret, S.S.J.; [music by] David Kraehenbuehl. -- text c.1972 by William H. Sadlier, Inc., music c.1972 by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript score (1 p.); 28 cm. (Box 5, Folder 86)
        Harmonized in 4 parts.
        In folder marked: Confirmation Song, St. Anthony of Padua, Hightstown, N.J., 1973.
      - Who am I? / [text by] Sr. James Margaret, S.S.J.; [music by] David Kraehenbuehl. -- text c.1972 by William H. Sadlier, Inc., music c.1972 by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript score (1 p.); 28 cm. (Box 5, Folder 86)
        Melody and text with chord symbols.
      - Earlier Compositions / David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript score (42 p); 31 cm. (Box 5, Folder 87)
        Rounds and Canons. -- Duochrome for String Quartet. -- Duochrome for String Orchestra and Flutes. -- [Music for a Christmas Play] -- Scherzo for String Quartet.
        On cover: Kate Neal Kinley Fellowship.
    - Teaching Pieces, I.H
      - Brandywine quick-step.
        see: [Marches, pianos (2), 8-hands. Brandywine quick-step]
      - Calendar scenes: a very first book of twelve-tone piano recital pieces / by David Kraehenbuehl. -- Minneapolis: Schmitt, Hall & McCreary Co., c.1966., 1 score (15 p.); 28 cm. (Box 5, Folder 88)
        Annotations in pencil.
        1. New Year's Party. -- 2. Valentine. -- 3. March Winds. -- 4. April Fool. -- 5. Memorial. -- 6. Vacation. -- 7. Fanfare for the Fourth. -- 8. Summer Clouds. -- 9. Labor Day Parade. -- 10. Trick or Treat. -- 11. Gray November. -- 12. Snow for Christmas.
      - A Christmas canzona: for one piano, four hands / by David Kraehenbuehl. -- Cincinnati: The Willis Music Co., c.1972., 1 score (15 p.); 31 cm. (Box 5, Folder 88)
        (David Kraehenbuehl Piano Ensemble Series)
        "Dedicated to Stanley Fletcher, with whom I first came to know this melody."
        Pl. no.: WMCo. 10613
      - Cube (Square rock)
        see: Keyboard Arts piano repertoire, Book 3.
      - Cuckoo rock.
        see: Keyboard Arts piano repertoire, Book 2.
      - Downhill rock., 1 manuscript score (6 p.); 32 cm. (Box 5, Folder 88)
        For piano 4 hands.
        In folder (discarded) marked: Shadow March - L.3
        In envelope (discarded) marked: !new beginnings! New School - 1953-60
      - Downhill rock / David Kraehenbuehl -- The New School for Music Study, c.1967., 1 manuscript score (2 p.); 35 cm. (Box 5, Folder 88)
        At end: May 30, 1967.
      - Earthmover.
        see: Keyboard arts piano repertoire, book 1.
      - Exploring the blues: jazz and rock stylings with study guides / by David Kraehenbuehl and Richard Chronister. -- New York: Carl Fischer, Inc., c.1979., 1 score (32 p.); 30 cm. (Box 5, Folder 89)
        Piledriver Blues -- Tie--dyed Rag -- Tiptoe Tango -- Daydreams -- Foggy Harbor -- High--iron Boogie -- Feelin' Good -- Soft Shoe -- Amen! Amen! -- End of the Trail -- Flying South -- Lazy Hound-dog -- Dizzy Disco -- So-long Rock.
        Pl. no.: 05062
      - Far Rockaway.
        see: Keyboard Arts piano repertoire, book 4.
      - General Burgoyne's march.
        see: [Marches, pianos (2), 8-hands. General Burgoyne's March]
      - Jubilation.
        see: Keyboard Arts piano repertoire, book 3.
      - Keyboard Arts piano repertoire. -- Princeton: National Keyboard Arts Association, c.1971-72., 6 scores (30 + 40 + 32 + 33 + 33 + 33 p.); 28 cm. (Box 6, Folder 90)
        Graded piano repertory by David Kraehenbuehl and other composers.
        "Each book in the Keyboard Arts Repertoire Series is designed to give the student performing experience with a complete cross-section of authentic music by composers from the late 18th century to our own time."
      - Keyboard theory / David Kraehenbuehl; with Frances Clark; and Louise Goss. -- Evanston, IL: Summy-Birchard, c.1965-66., 4 v. (192 p. total); 28 cm. (Box 6, Folder 91)
        Volumes 1, 2, 3, and 6.
      - Lonesome rock.
        see: Keyboard Arts piano repertoire, book 1.
      - Lost rock.
        see: Keyboard Arts piano repertoire, book 6.
      - [Marches, pianos (2), 8-hands. Brandywine quick-step] Brandywine quick-step / Anonymous. -- c.1976 by National Keyboard Arts Associates., 4 p. of manuscript music; 22 x 28 cm. (Box 6, Folder 92)
        Photocopy of manuscript.
        In envelope with other David Kraehenbuehl compositions labeled Family pieces.
      - [Marches, pianos (2), 8-hands. General Burgoyne's March] General Burgoyne's March / Anonymous. -- c.1976 by National Keyboard Arts Associates., 8 p. of manuscript music; 22 x 28 cm. (Box 6, Folder 92)
      - [Marches, pianos (2), 8-hands. Successful campaign] Successful campaign / Anonymous. -- c.1976 by National Keyboard Arts Associates., 4 p. of manuscript music; 22 x 28 cm. (Box 6, Folder 92)
      - [Marches, pianos (2), 8-hands. Washington's march] Washington's march / Anonymous. -- c.1976 by National Keyboard Arts Associates., 4 p. of manuscript music; 22 x 28 cm. (Box 6, Folder 92)
      - [Marches concertantes; arr.] Marches concertantes: a short concerto for young people / by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 score (47 p.); 28 cm. (Box 6, Folder 92)
        Accompaniment arr. for second piano.
        I. March rondeau. -- II. Marche solennelle. -- III. Marche vite.
        At end: Cranbury, N.J., Dec. 19, 1973.
      - [Marches concertantes; arr.] Marches concertantes: a short piano concerto for young people / by David Kraehenbuehl. -- New York: Carl Fischer, Inc., c.1978., 1 score (40 p.); 31 cm. (Box 6, Folder 92)
        "To Rebecca Migliore, who first performed this concerto."
        At end: December 19, 1973, Cranbury, N.J.
        Pl. no.: N5990
      - Orangutan rock.
      - [Rhapsody in rock; arr.] Rhapsody in rock: a concerto in one movement / by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 score (25 p.); 28 cm. (Box 6, Folder 93)
        At end: January 29, 1974, Cranbury, N.J.
      - [Rhapsody in rock; arr.] Rhapsody in rock: a concerto in one movement for piano / by David Kraehenbuehl. -- New York: Carl Fischer, c.1976., 1 score (24 p.); 31 cm. (Box 6, Folder 93)
        At end: January 24, 1974, Cranbury, N.J.
        Pl. no.: N5973
      - Rock candy.
        see: Keyboard Arts piano repertoire, book 5.
      - Rock pile.
      - Rockin' off.
      - Rocky Road.
      - Rooster rock.
      - Runaway toccata.
      - Snowscape.
        see: Keyboard Arts piano repertoire, book 2.
      - Successful campaign.
        see: [Marches, pianos (2), 8-hands. Successful campaign]
      - Turquoise.
      - Variations in the form of a suite on a theme by Larry Kettelkamp / David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript score (2 p.); 35 cm. (Box 6, Folder 93)
        Holograph in ink, annotations in pencil and colored pencil.
        For piano.
        Prelude. -- Allemande. -- Courante. -- Sarabande. -- Bourree. -- Gigue.
      - Washington's march.
        see: [Marches, pianos (2), 8-hands. Washington's march]
    - Roman Catholic Service Music, I.I
      - Danish amen mass: SATB choir, congregation, organ / David Kraehenbuehl; Charles Frischmann. -- Schiller Park, IL: J. S. Paluch Co., c.1973., 1 score (11 p.); 28 cm. (Box 6, Folder 94)
      - Danish amen mass. (Box 6, Folder 94)
        Additional / alternate settings, 7 p.
      - Folk mass. (Box 6, Folder 94)
        Additional / alternate setting, 5 p.
      - [Hymns arranged or harmonized by David Kraehenbuehl] (Box 6, Folder 95)
        Accept, almighty Father
        Alleluia! Sing to Jesus!
        Ascend, ascend, o noble Queen
        Christ the Lord, is ris'n today
        Come, holy ghost
        Draw near, o Lord
        Hail, hail Queen enthroned above